Chapter 2. Word Linking and Phrasing. Run your words together. As mentioned in the
previous chapter, in American English, words are not pronounced one by one.
Usually, the end-of-one word attaches to the beginning of the next word. This is
also true for initials, numbers, and spelling. Part of the glue that connects
sentences is an underlying hum or drone that only breaks when you come to a period
and sometimes not even then. You have this underlying hum in your own language, and
it helps a great deal toward making you sound like a native speaker. Once you have
a strong intonation, you need to connect all those stair steps together so that
each sentence sounds like one long word. This chapter is going to introduce you to
the idea of liaisons, the connections between words, which allow us to speak in
sound groups rather than in individual words. Just as we went over where to put
intonation, here you're going to learn how to connect words. Once you learn to use this
technique, you can make the important leap from this practice book to other materials
in your own conversation. To make it easier for you to read, liaisons are
written like this. They tell me that I'm easier to understand. It could also be written, they
tell me that I'm easier to understand, but it would be too hard to read.